

# Stephen A Thomas Front End Web Development

stephen@sathomas.me

+1 (404) 457-8652

ħ http://jsDataV.is

http://sathomas.me

github.com/sathomas

@stephen thomas

### **About Me**

Front end architect with extensive experience in modern web development and a zeal for delivering exceptional user experiences. Noted expert and invited speaker on interactive, web-based data visualization. Thorough understanding of front end development based on the principles of accessibility, progressive enhancement and responsive design. Introduced and tutored development teams in the adoption of leading front end technologies such as MV • frameworks and test-driven development. Work experience includes corporate enterprises and service providers, as well as charitable support of non-profit organizations including the Centers for Disease Control and the World Health Organization. Author of multiple books on web technology and frequent speaker at leading industry conferences.

# Skills & Areas of Expertise

JavaScript	•	•	•	•	•
HTML5	•	•	•	•	•
CSS3		•	•	•	•
D3.js	•		•	•	•
Backbone.js	•			•	•
jQuery	•			•	0
Responsive Design		•		•	0
Progressive Enhancement				•	0
Test Driven Development	•			•	0
Accessibility				0	0

## Work Experience

Front End Developer at Intellum 2015 - Present

Primary front end developer for enterprise learning management system.

Application Developer at Georgia Tech 2013 - 2015

Web developer in Office of Education Technology focussed on largescale web platforms for academic research and collaboration.

Front End Architect at Dell SecureWorks 2007 - 2013

Responsible for all aspects of front end design and development for web and mobile applications.

Chief Architect at Wave7 Optics 2001 - 2006

Led design and development of IP-based optical network architecture for the delivery of video, voice and data services in business and residential applications.

#### **Publications**

Data Visualization with JavaScript. No Starch: San Francisco, 2015.

"Simple Responsive Images With CSS Background Images." published 22 July 2013 on *Smashing Magazine*.

"Unit Testing Backbone.js Applications." published 25 February 2013 on *JSPRO.com*.

"Web-Based Visualization." published 5 November 2012 on UICloud.

HTTP Essentials: Protocols for Secure, Scaleable Web Sites. John Wiley & Sons: New York, 2001.

SSL & TLS Essentials: Securing the Web. John Wiley & Sons: New York, 2000.

#### **Education**

Candidate for PhD in Quantitative BioSciences (sponsored by School of Mathematics). Georgia Institute of Technology. Atlanta, Georgia (part-time beginning Fall 2016).

Master of Science from School of Electrical Engineering. Georgia Institute of Technology. Atlanta, Georgia. 1994. GPA: 4.0 (A=4).